Jacob Smith

Software Engineer & Digital Marketer

205-356-5423

jacobxxsmith@gmail.com

iacobsmith.site

Birmingham, AL

Developer at heart with a digital marketing mindset who is motivated by measurable results. Active team-member and contributor when collaborating with distributed work-groups. Experience in creating real world solutions for critical client issues and needs.

Work Experience

Founder/CEO

Feb. 2022 - Present | The Knob Shoppe

- Build custom guitar pedal clones and modded clones
- Upkeep of Woocommerce powered Wordpress store
- Write content for and distribute Double Scoop newsletter
- Manage The Knob Shoppe/Double Scoop social media

Web Developer & Digital Marketer

March 2020 - Present | ADTRAV

- Total website management including DNS, domains, backups, SSL's, plugins, updates
- Custom code creation utilizing API's
- Manage digital marketing campaigns with CRM emails, forms, landing pages, and strategies

Website Support Specialist

Nov. 2018 - March 2020 | High Level Marketing

- Launch and QA custom Wordpress sites
- Create custom functionality for new and existing websites
- Maintain, update, and bugfix existing client websites



Education

Jefferson State Community College

2018 | Full Stack Web Development

Jacksonville State University

2011-2013 | Computer Science

Skillset

•••• HTML/CSS

•••• Wordpress

••• Javascript

●●● PHP/MySQL

••• DNS Management

••• Team Management

••• Project Management